Marden Braulio Arteaga Lescano

□ (+51) 962-607-427 | 🗷 marden.arteaga@unmsm.edu.pe | 🖸 braulio-arteaga | 🛅 braulioarteaga | 🔰 @BraulioArt23

Summary_

Bachelor's degree in Economics from Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos with Master's degree courses in Public Policy from Universidad del Rosario. Three years of experience in applied microeconomics. Interest in research on development economics and impact evaluation. Working affinity with institutions of synergy between academia, the public sector, and multilateral organizations.

Education

Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos

Lima, Perú

FACULTY OF ECONOMICS SCIENCES

March 2016 - April 2022

Bachelor in Economics

Universidad del Rosario

Bogotá, Colombia

Master of Public Policy January 2021 - November 2021

Completed courses: Impact evaluation, Public economy and Computational methods for public policy

Experience _____

Innovations for Poverty Action

Lima, Perú

Research analyst

October 2022 - Present

- Collaboration in a project evaluating the impact of the migratory regularization on the quality of life of Venezuelan migrants in Peru.
- Collaboration in a project to evaluate the impact of a microfinance program in a rural area of Paraguay.
- · Field monitoring and data cleaning

Innovations for Poverty Action

Lima, Perú

Research intern

November 2021 - October 2022

- Collaboration on projects to mitigate the adverse effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on early childhood distance education in Costa Rica and Guatemala.
- Survey programming, data cleaning and report generation.

Universidad Peruana Cayetano Heredia

Lima, Perú

HEALTH INNOVATION LAB

Research assistant

February 2022 - December 2022

- Collaboration in research about excess mortality during the COVID-19 pandemic.
- Data cleaning, descriptive and spatial analysis.

Ministry of Housing, Construction and Sanitation

Lima, Perú

IMPACT EVALUATION OFFICE

March 2020 - November 2021

- Research Intern
- Collaboration in quasi-experimental evaluation of rural sanitation and urban infrastructure.
- Data cleaning, descriptive and spatial analysis.

Awards and Honors _____

2023	Scholarship , Lima Summer School of Economics	Lima, Perú
	ORGANIZER: Vancouver School of Economics and Universidad de Piura	Liiia, Peru
2022	First place, CIES Partner Training Program	Linea David
	ORGANIZER: Consorcio de Investigación Económica y Social - CIES	Lima, Perú
2021	Winning team, IV International Contest of Impact Evaluation for better governance	Lima. Perú
	ORGANIZER: Development Bank of Latin America - CAF	Lima, Pera
2021	Scholarship , Multidisciplinary Artificial Intelligence Program	Rushas Aires Argentina
	Organizador: Universidad de Buenos Aires - UBA	Buenos Aires, Argentina
2020	Scholarship , Winter School	Bogotá, Colombia
	Organizer: Universidad del Rosario - UR	Бодоца, Соютына

Skills Software Stata, R, Python, SurveyCTO, Web Scraping y Markdown Languages English (intermediate) and Spanish (native) **Work in Progress** Excess mortality during COVID-19 pandemic in Peru: A Spatio- temporal assessment of main contributors WITH GABRIEL CARRASCO AND JESÚS QUISPE The impact of peruvian agroindustry WITH CHRIS BOYD AND CRISTINA CHIARELLA **Publications** Determinants of payment for water service in rural Peru WITH DENNYS JESUSI AND AUGUSTO MENDOZA - MINISTRY OF HOUSING, CONSTRUCTION AND SANITATION Impact evaluation of the Comprehensive Neighborhood Improvement Program on citizen insecurity WITH DENNYS JESUSI AND AUGUSTO MENDOZA - MINISTRY OF HOUSING, CONSTRUCTION AND SANITATION Impact evaluation of the National Urban Sanitation Program on health and infant mortality WITH AUGUSTO MENDOZA - MINISTRY OF HOUSING, CONSTRUCTION AND SANITATION **Complementary education**

Difference in Differences: foundations and new methodology

Lima, Perú

2022 - Present

2023 - Present

2021

2021

2021

VANCOUVER SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS AND UNIVERSIDAD DE PIURA

March 2023

Crisis and Recuperation: Data Science Applied to Public Policy

Santiago, Chile

Universidad de Chile

December 2022

Manage Successful Impact Evaluation Surveys

Washington D. C, EE.UU.

WORLD BANK

December 2022

References _____

Chris, Boyd

Ph.D. IN APPLIED ECONOMICS

- Institution: Towson University EEUU
- E-mail: chrismarilynboyd@gmail.com

Gshan, Irigoin

ASSOCIATE RESEARCH MANAGER

- Institution: Innovations for Poverty Action Perú
- E-mail: girigoin@poverty-action.org